Thank you for letting me
be your mom.
（クシナ）私を母にしてくれて
ありがとう。
ミナトを父にしてくれて　ありがとう。
And thank you for letting
Minato be your dad.
私たちのもとに→
Thank you for being...
born to us!
生まれてきてくれて→
本当に…　ありがとう。
Thank you...
Thank you so much.
《ナルト：母ちゃん…。
Mom...
これからは　ラーメンばっかりでなくて
野菜もちゃんと食うってばよ。
From now on,
I promise I'll eat vegetables
and not just ramen.
風呂は好きだから　安心してくれ。
温泉にも　よく行ってるし…。
I like taking baths,
so don't worry about that.
I go to the hot springs a lot too.
それにいつも
いっぱい寝てるしよ。
And I get lots of sleep.
つぅか　寝過ぎぐらいだってばよ。
In fact, I sleep too much,
ya know!
友達に関しちゃ
いいヤツらがいっぱいできたんだ。
As for friends,
I have lots of good ones.
母ちゃんにも
会わせてやりたかったな。
I wish you could have met them.
ただ…　一人だけ→
There's one that I'm not
getting along with though.
うまくいかねえヤツが
いるんだけどよ。
勉強のことはまぁ…
母ちゃんの予想どおりだ。
As for studying...
Well, you feared right, Mom.
もちろん
落ち込んでねえってばよ。
But I don't get depressed
over that, ya know!
アカデミー時代は　先生や先輩と
いろいろあったけど→
A lot happened with my teachers
and upperclassmen
during my Academy days,
今では　みんな尊敬してる。
but we respect each other now.
忍の三禁は
自来也先生に教えてもらった。
Master Jiraiya taught me about
the Three Shinobi Prohibitions.
たしかに　母ちゃんの
言うとおりの人だったけど→
You were right about him, Mom!
俺の忍としての生き方も
教えてくれた。
But he's the one who taught me
how a shinobi should live!
偉大な忍だってばよ。
He was a great shinobi.
俺は　木ノ葉の忍者
うずまきナルトだ。
I'm Naruto Uzumaki,
a ninja of the Hidden Leaf!
夢は　火影の名を受け継ぐこと。
My dream is to become the Hokage!
そんで　先代の
どの火影をも超えてやること！》
And I'll surpass all the Hokage
who came before me!
そんで　父ちゃんより
カッケー男になる！
And I'm going to be cooler
than Dad!
そんで
母ちゃんより強ぇ忍になる！
And I'm going to be
a stronger shinobi than you, Mom!
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
Battle in Paradise! Odd Beast vs. The Monster!
おっしゃ！
All right!
What happened?
（ヤマト）何があった？
うまくいったのか？
Did it go well?
とにかく　いろいろあって…。
A lot of things happened.
（キラービー）ヨー！
Yo!
そうか　そういうことか。　了解。
お前の顔　今　涼感！
I see! I get it!
Understood!
Your expression now is looking good!
九尾はどうなった？
コントロールはできたのか？
What about the Nine Tails?
Did you get it under control?
いや～　よかったぜ。
特に　あれのときのこれがヨウ。
That's real good news.
Especially when you used it,
in that situation, yo!
ヘヘヘヘ…。
オウ　ナルト！
お前　それってよ　まさか！？
Whoa, Naruto!
Don't tell me that by that, you mean...
You know what?!
うん　そうなんだってばよ。
Yup!
That's right, ya know!
だから　何があったか
話せと言っている！
So tell me what happened!
あれ　これ　それでは
わかりません！
This, that... How am I supposed
to understand?!
わざとだ！
キミたちは　わざとやっている！
This is all on purpose!
You're talking like that on purpose!
それだけはわかるぞ～っ！
That much I know!
What?!
（ガイ）なんだと！
ナルトが　そんな大変な修業を！？
Naruto's going through
harsh training like that?!
青春のなかで　もがく若者を
放ってはおけない！
I can't ignore a young man
struggling during the springtime
of his youth!
ナルトのところへ案内しろ！
Take me to Naruto!
（アオバ）この人　ちょっと
あれなんで…。
He... is a bit eccentric.
すみません。
（モトイ）いえ…。
So I apologize.
It's all right.
安心してくれ　ヤマト隊長。
Relax, Captain Yamato.
I have the Nine Tails' chakra safe
九尾のチャクラは　俺の中の別の場所に
ちゃんと取ってある。
in a separate place inside me.
いつも使ってるってわけじゃねえ。
So that I'm not using it all the time.
This is how it is when I use
the Nine Tails' chakra.
これが　九尾のチャクラを
使ったときの感じだってばよ。
（ヤマト）すごい…　生命力が満ちてる。
Amazing...
It's overflowing with life energy.
おぉ…。
僕の木遁が影響を受けるなんて。
I can't believe my Wood Style
is affected by it.
何？
それで隠れてるつもりかよ！
What?
You really think...
you're hidden?
何か　別のチャクラを感じるのか？
Do you sense some other chakra?
感じるんだな　別の存在。
それに気づけぬ俺は　ぞんざい。
He senses another's proximity...
That I couldn't, was hasty of me.
《鬼鮫：ありえない。
私のチャクラは鮫肌と同じ。
Impossible!
My chakra is the same as Samehada.
気づかれるはずがない》
There's no way
anyone could sense it!
チャクラじゃねえ。　なんか　こう…
モヤモヤした悪意みたいのを感じる。
It's not chakra!
It feels hazy... something sinister.
それだ！　その…。
That's it! That thing!
刀！？
The sword?
It seems that you can sense hatred
and feelings of evil.
（鬼鮫）憎しみや悪の感情を
感じ取るようですね。
感知タイプの
どれにも当てはまらない。
The limitations of Sensory-Types
don't apply.
それが　九尾のコントロールを成した
人柱力の力ですか。
Is that the power of a Jinchuriki
who has mastery
over the Nine Tails?
お前は…　暁の鮫野郎。
You're the shark guy of the Akatsuki!
なぜだ？　あのとき
コイツの首をはねたはずだ。
How? I thought we chopped
his head off a ways back...
((雷影：やるぞ。
Let's do this!
オーケー　ブラザー。
Okay... Brother!
（鬼鮫）水遁　大鮫弾の…。
Water Style: Super Shark—!
(ダブルラリアット！！))
– Double Lariat!
How did you manage to escape
our tag-team attack?
どうやって
俺とブラザーのタッグ攻撃を外した？
水の塊で戦ったとき→
I simply switched out
while we battled inside
the bubble of water.
水中で　既に
入れ替わっただけですよ。
《これは墨…　目くらまし。
Ink... A smokescreen.
やっぱり　タコ野郎ですね。
You are an octopus, after all.
が…》
However...
With my body merged to Samehada,
((この　鮫肌と融合した私の体は→
I can detect chakra
through my skin.
(チャクラを　肌で感じ取る))
首をはねられたのは　私の分身。
You cut off my clone's head.
((ゼツ：やりすぎじゃないの？
Don't you think you're overdoing it?
八尾には　あれぐらいが
ちょうど　いいでしょう。
Don't you think that was
just right for the Eight-Tails?
（ゼツ）じゃあ
ここからは僕の仕事だ。
I guess it's my turn now.
(よろしく　お願いします))
I leave it in your hands.
分身なら
殺されたとき　消えるはずだ。
Clones disappear
when they're struck!
死体は　実際　そこにあった。
これ　疑問。
The corpse remained
post-mortem... no question.
それに　別の者が変化してたなら
うちのシーが感知で気づく。
And if someone else had
transformed into you,
Shee would have sensed it.
これ　難問。
So it's a perplexing consternation.
特別な分身でしてね。
It was a special kind of clone.
A Parasitic Clone that I can
manipulate remotely.
自分自身として
遠隔操作できる寄生分身。
と　まあ　その話は
このへんで　いいでしょう。
Anyway, enough about this subject.
Now then, two Jinchuriki
and a Wood Style user...
しかし　人柱力　２人と
木遁使い相手に　この私の状況。
I am in a serious predicament.
正直　きついですね。
なに！？　どうして　この部屋の
扉の開け方を知っている？
What?
How did you know the way to
open the door to this room?!
That's a silly question.
愚問ですね。　私は　スパイとして
ここに入ったんですよ。
I came here to spy.
ぐはっ！
Was that the Teleportation Jutsu?
瞬身の術なのか。
The first smash...
いきなり先攻。
これじゃまるで黄色い閃光。
Just like the Yellow Flash!
《くっ　速い。　ここまでとは》
So fast... I didn't expect that.
ん？　うわっ！
足が…　勢いあまって
突っ込みすぎた！
My foot!
I had so much force,
I hit it too hard!
まだ　四代目のようには
いかないみたいだね。
It seems you're not up to
the Fourth Hokage's level yet.
Bee! Please go after him!
ビーさん　ヤツを追いかけてください。
僕はナルトを。
お　おう！
I'll see to Naruto.
Right! Leave the chase to me.
I'll catch him in a jiffy.
任せろ追跡　すぐに追撃。
うっ…　クソ！
（ガイ）何　滝の中から
真実の自分が現れるだと？
What?
Your true self appears from
inside the waterfall?
本当にそんなことが。
Is that for real?
（モトイ）ああ　ナルトもここで
真実の自分に打ち勝ったようだ。
Yes. Naruto faced and defeated
his true self at this very spot.
ガイさんも
やってみたらどうですか？
Guy, why don't you try it out
for yourself?
バカを言え！　そんなことより
ナルトの応援に行くのが先だ。
Don't be stupid!
We have to go and
help Naruto first!
俺は　ナルトを守る先生として
ここに来たんだ。
I came here as a teacher
to protect Naruto!
そ　そんなに怒らなくても。
Don't get so upset.
本当は自分の真実を知るのが
怖いだけなんじゃないですか？
Are you afraid to face
your true self?
ひょっとして。
アハハハッ　何を！
Is that it?
What did you say?
俺が怖がっているとでも？
You think I'm scared?
ノープロブレム！
No problem!
いや　冗談ですよ！
No, I was just joking.
たぶん本性は
人ではない気がしますが　アハハハッ。
I have a feeling
your true self isn't human.
そんな本気にしなくても…。
Don't take me so seriously.
正直　青春青春って
言ってる場合でもないだろう。
Honestly, you really shouldn't be
going on about "youth," should you?
老けたおっさんが
無理をすると体を壊すぞ。
Overdoing things can hurt
a man past his prime like you.
リーの手前　青春でいかなきゃ
いけないのは　わかるが。
I know you have to keep up
appearances for Lee's sake.
誰もそんな
お前の無理やりな青春を→
But no one expects you to
force yourself to stay youthful.
望んでなんか
いないんじゃないか？
姿を見せろ！
言いたいことを言わせておけば。
Show yourself!
You can say what you like
to my face!
いいだろう。
真実のお前を　とくと知るが…。
Fine.
You can take a long,
hard look at your true self.
こ　これが俺の本当の姿？
Is this my true self?!
珍虫！
An Odd Insect?
I'm sure this is...
the Odd Beast!
《コイツは確か珍獣》
なに？
What?!
青春を忘れた俺。
お前の根性を叩き直す！
Hey me! The one who has
forgotten what youth is!
I'll beat some sense into you!
ガイさん！
ソイツは真実のアンタじゃない！
Guy!
That's not your true self!
注意しろ！
うお～っ　木ノ葉！
Watch out!
Leaf Rock...
壊岩升！
Crushing Square!
うおっ！
え？　俺の真実の姿じゃない。
It's not my true self.
よく見てください。
Take a good look!
どう見ても違うでしょ。
It's not you,
no matter how you look at it!
目を開けた時点で
真実の滝から出てしまうんだ。
The moment you open your eyes,
you leave the Waterfall of Truth!
コ　コイツは確か…。
This is... I'm certain it's...
フグとかいう魚。
the fish they call puffer fish!
いや…　ハリセンボンだったかな？
No... Maybe it was
a porcupine fish?
このへん一帯は
珍しい生き物が多いですからね。
This region has lots
of strange creatures, so...
って　フグですかあれ。
Is that really a puffer fish?
It's supposed to be real tasty.
食べるとおいしいんですよね。
無理やり間違えてんのか
アンタたちは！
Are you all deliberately
playing the fool?
相変わらず頭のほうは
珍獣以下ですね。
I see that you are still dumber
than a beast.
ソイツは　スパイの暁。
He's an Akatsuki agent!
逃がせば情報がもれて赤っ恥。
If he escapes,
they'll get intel on us.
And that would be
a huge abasement!
鮫肌め。
Damn you, Samehada...
コイツは　たしか
イタチと組んでいた暁の鮫男。
He's the shark fellow
of the Akatsuki
who was teamed up with Itachi.
弱っているようですが…。
He looks weakened.
どうやって入ってきた？
How did he get in?
（鮫肌）ギギギギ…。
そうかそうか　無理やり…。
I see, I see... He forced you.
That must've been pretty tough.
そりゃ大変だったろうな。
ギギ…　ギギギギ…。
That's kind of creepy.
ある意味キモイな…。
ギギギギ！
ヘヘヘヘ　コラコラ！　ジャレ方が乱暴。
Hey, hey! Don't play too rough!
But what can I say,
I got the right stuff!
好かれるのが　俺様の人望。
（アオバ）しまった！？　ヤツが水の中へ！
Damn it! He's underwater!
ヤツは水遁系の！
He's a Water Style user!
わかっている。
I'm aware of that.
ビー　気づけ！
Bee, watch out!
チャクラを取られているぞ！
He's taking your chakra!
うん？
Huh?
強い人ってのは　なんでこう
鈍感なんですかね　ったく！
Why do strong people tend to
be pretty dense, damn it?!
はぁ？　おっ！
Cut it out STAT...
やめろって！　お前が　かわいくて
力が抜けていく～。
But you're so cute that...
I'm getting weak in the knees...
うぅ…。
ガイさん！　援護お願いします！
逆に情報を取ってやります！
Guy! Please assist me!
I'm going to get data
from him instead!
秘術　石針！
Hidden Jutsu! Stone Needles!
よし！
All right!
A jutsu where chakra is poured
in to stop my movement.
《チャクラを流し込んで
動きを止める術か？
だが　それは好都合！》
Now that's perfect!
《ぐっ…　逆に
チャクラを吸い取られているのか？
Is he absorbing my chakra instead?
うっ…　なんて吸引力だ》
So much pull!
木ノ葉旋風！
Leaf Hurricane!
うっ！？
《チャクラは十分　復活しましたね》
You got all your chakra back.
水遁！　水鮫弾の術！
Water Style!
Shark Bomb Jutsu!
うわっ！　おっ！
（モトイ）しまった！？　逃げられた！
Damn it, he got away!
速いぞ！　この島の
結界の外へ出したら終わりだ！
He's fast!
If he gets past the barrier
around this island, it's all over.
それまでにしとめないと
俺でも感知できなくなる！
We must stop him before that,
because my sensory powers
won't work then.
俺が止めてやる！
I'll stop him!
The Eight Inner Gates!
八門遁甲！　第六景門　開！
The Sixth Gate of Joy: Open!
（キングちゃん）ウホ！？
Let yourself be captured by
the arms of my Eight Tails...
俺の八尾の腕につかまれ珍獣！
Odd Beast!
Far, far away you'll go...
ぶん投げてやる！　方向は十時だ！
In the direction of
ten o'clock I'll throw.
韻を踏むために
いい加減なことを言うな！
Don't sacrifice the truth just
for a rhyme!
方向は　二時だ！
He went towards two o'clock!
よし！
All right!
うぃ～！！
イッ　イィ…。
ビー　大丈夫か？
ギギギ。
Are you all right, Bee?
俺はオーケー　すぐに回復…。
I'm okay.
I'll be good right away.
ムチャクチャ　チャクラを
取られちゃってんじゃないっすか。
You got a lot of chakra
taken away from you!
けど　まだ今なら止められるかも。
We may be able to stop him.
ナルトとヤマトは
この滝の奥でしたよね？
Naruto and Yamato are behind
this waterfall, right?
イッテテ…　足をひねったってばよ。
I twisted my ankle.
力のコントロールには
今後は気をつけないと。
Be careful about keeping
your power under control!
よし！　いくよ！
All right. Let's go!
うん！
Yeah!
チッ！
頼むぞ！
I'm counting on you!
久しぶりに
出てきたと思ったら空！？
I was going to say it's been a while...
but really, midair?
背中を借りる！
I'm going to borrow your back!
うおっ！　うわぁ～！！
イテテテテ…。
Ouch!!
Damn it, Guy!
Using me as a stepping-stone!
ガイのヤツ　わしを踏み台にしおって！
Up we go.
よっこいしょ！
ん？　おっ！？
ど…　どうも。
H-Hello...
Looks like I gave them the slip.
《よし　うまくまけたようですね》
口寄せの術！
Summoning Jutsu...
しつこい方ですね。
You're persistent!
見たぞ！　その鮫に託した巻物が
情報だな？　逃がしはしないぞ！！
So... That scroll you gave to that
shark contains intel on us.
I won't let you get away!
できますかね？
こちらには　地の利がありますが。
I wouldn't be so sure.
I have the geographical advantage.
水遁　千食鮫！
Water Style!
Thousand Hungry Sharks!
チッ！　これでは
どれが　どれだか　わからんザメ…。
I don't know which shark is which.
こうなれば…。
In that case...!
はぁ～！
アチャ　チャ　チャ　チャ　チャ！
朝孔雀！
Asakujaku!
♪～
Where's the scroll?
《巻物は…？
Damn it.
There are too many of them.
クソ！　多すぎるか。
It can't be helped.
I have to cover a wider area.
しかたない。
まとめて　面倒みてやるぞ》
（鬼鮫）水中の鮫も
行かせない気ですね。
He won't let the sharks
in the water go either.
Fine.
いいでしょう。
バラバラにしてさしあげますよ。
I'll just let them tear you apart!
第七驚門　開！
The Seventh Gate of Shock!
Open!
なるほど…。
I see...
（鬼鮫）正拳のあまりの速さに
空気摩擦で炎を宿し→
A taijutsu that crushes opponents
with a shock wave
of air and flames created from
the friction of punched air!
空気を叩く衝撃波と炎で
相手を破壊する体術！
An Odd Beast indeed.
A shinobi with taijutsu
this powerful is truly rare.
まさに　珍獣…
これほど　体術の強い忍は珍しい。
私は３度目ですが。
This will be the third time for me.
次の体術は　さっきのとは
比べものにならぬ　一撃必殺の拳。
The next taijutsu will be nothing
like the previous ones.
It's a special single-blow attack.
It's something you'll rarely see...
めったに見られるものではない。
The blue chakra is pushing
the water away.
碧いチャクラが水を押しのけるとはね。
水遁　大鮫弾の術！
Water Style!
Super Shark Bomb Jutsu!
昼虎！
Hirudora!
たぁ～！
うぉ～！
This Super Shark Bomb is
no ordinary jutsu.
《この大鮫弾は
ただの術ではありませんよ。
The jutsu itself absorbs chakra
and becomes even stronger.
術自体が　チャクラを吸収する。
そして　更に　大きく　強くなる。
相手の忍術が
強ければ強いほどにね》
And the stronger
the opponent's ninjutsu,
the stronger it gets.
What's going on?
どういうことです！？
I exhausted his jutsu...
ヤツの術は収縮したのに
大鮫弾が大きくならない！
but my Super Shark Bomb
isn't getting stronger?!
I know I absorbed his chakra!
チャクラは吸収したはず…。
Was that not
a chakra Energy Bomb?!
これは　チャクラの気弾ではないのか！？
Roar, my youth!
吠えろ　青春！
うわ～！
♪～
kotae nakute mo ii sa sagashi tsuzukeru n da yo
You don't have to answer, I'll keep on searching
sou otona ni naru jikan da ne
Yeah, I guess it's time to grow up
imasugu tsugetai kedo furue ga tomaranai
I want to tell you right now but I can't stop this shaking
kokoro wa ima sara nigete to sakebu no sa
My heart shouts for me to run away, even now
by my side by my side
By my side, By my side
tatoeba anata no me no oku ni
In the depth of your eyes, if there's a scenery you seek
motomeru keshiki ga aru no nara
sore wo tsukande tashikametai n da
I want to grasp it and see for myself
moshi kimi no namida ga kono sekai wo
If your tears have set you apart from this world
kimi kara toozaketa toshitemo
boku wa sono te hanasanai n da
I won't let go of your hand
dakara sou ima
So, yes... right now
i need you here right by my side
by my side
By my side
Next Episode
In the Hidden Mist, here is a great obstacle one must overcome
（美空）
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
to be a true shinobi...
美空ひばりです。
The sensation of killing your own comrade is indescribable.
では最後まで　ごゆっくり→
お楽しみください。
I will say that I felt I was trapped in a false existence.
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "The Man Named Kisame"
The Man Named Kisame
This world really is full of lies.